Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Papers AIA.031.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Papers
1806-2014
1975-2000
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Moloney, Mick, 1944-
AIA.031.003
37.5 Linear Feet in 34 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 5 flat files folders
2 websites in two archived websites.
The Mick Moloney Irish-American and Popular Culture Papers are a subcollection of the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection consisting of papers acquired and produced in the course of Moloney's career as a folklorist, producer, musician, and academic. The papers include research, administrative, and personal files; materials related to song and music collection; concert posters, programs, and other memorabilia; and photographs related to all aspects of Moloney's professional life.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Collection is composed of five parts. Taken together, they illustrate Dr. Moloney's career long engagement with Irish-American culture across a wide variety of media with a particular focus on Irish and Irish-American music.
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Commercial Recordings (AIA 031.1)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings (AIA 031.2)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana (AIA 031.4)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Videotapes (AIA 031.5)
Dorothy Hayden Cudahy Irish Memories Collection (AIA 001) Susan McKeown Papers (AIA 032)
Arrangement
This subcollection is arranged in seven series. All of the series are arranged alphabetically, with the exception of Series V. Concert Memoribilia, which is arranged chronologically.
Series I: General, 1806-2011
Series II: Individuals, 1879-2010
Series III: Academic, 1889-2011
Series IV: Song and Music Collecting, 1867-2000
Series V: Concert Memorabilia, 1971-2011
Series VI: Photographs, circa 1930-2002
Series VII: Archived Websites, 2014-ongoing
Historical/Biographical Note
Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-) is a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He has recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States.
Moloney is the author of Far from the Shamrock Shore (2002) and numerous essays on Irish music and musical culture, and the co-editor of Close to the Floor: Irish Dance from the Boreen to Broadway (2009).
Sources:
Steve Winnick, "From Limerick Rake to Solid Man: The Musical Life of Mick Moloney," Dirty Linen, No. 48 (October/November 1993)
1999 NEA National Heritage Fellowships: http://www.nea.gov/honors/heritage/fellows/fellow.php?id=1999_11
Mick Moloney, Musician and Folklorist: http://www.mickmoloney.com
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Custodial History Note
New York University's Division of Libraries, in conjunction with Glucksman Ireland House at New York University, purchased the Mick Moloney Collection for the Archives of Irish America in 2006. Until the Collection was transferred to New York University, under the supervision of Dr. Michael Nash, Head of the Tamiment Library, the materials were stored in Dr. Moloney's house in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2006.071 and 2010.019.
http://mickmoloney.com/index.html was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2014 as part of the Arts and Cultural Left Web Archive. n 2015, this website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2019, http://mickmoloney.com/ was added to the web archive to replace http://mickmoloney.com/index.html. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.130.
Scope and Content Note
The Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Papers document Dr. Moloney's academic, professional, and performative interests and activities. This subcollection consists of research, administrative, and personal files; scholarly literature on folklore and ethnicity; materials related to song and music collecting; concert posters, programs, and other memorabilia; and photographs. The materials illustrate themes such as immigration and assimilation viewed through the lens of Irish-America's engagement with and expression of its own popular culture, with specific emphasis on its musical traditions. The time period most heavily documented in this subcollection (1975-2000) witnessed both a reinvestment by Irish-America in its cultural traditions and a transition of its musical traditions from the home to the stage, accompanied by unprecedented national recognition. The subcollection illustrates the shifts in policies regarding arts funding and programming; the valorization of ethnicity in the United States during the late 20th century; the rise in prominence of female performers of traditional music; and the Irish presence on and repertoire of the Philadelphia and New York music scenes.
Appraisal
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Session (seisun).; Washington (D.C.); Concerts.; Competitions.; Irish Americans -- Music.; Irish -- Songs and music.; Boston (Mass.); Interviews.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Cleveland (Ohio); Music schools.; Chicago (Ill.); Philadelphia (Pa.); New York (N.Y.).; Oral history.; Irish Americans.; Music |x Competitions.; Irish -- Music; Music festivals.; Carroll, Liz, 1957-; Britton, Tim; O'Donnell, Eugene, 1932-; McComiskey, Billy; Ivers, Eileen; McGlynn, Sean; Rafferty, Mike, 1926-; Egan, Seamus, 1969-; Keane, Jimmy; Coen, Jack; O'Connell, Robbie; Coen, Charlie, Fr., 1934-; Neary, Eleanor Kane, 1915-1993; Keane, James, 1948-; Ochs, Bill; Cahill, Eddie; Caulfield, Tommy, 1903-1987; McGreevy, Johnny, 1919-
- Series I: General, 1806-2011; 14 boxes
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: General, 1806-2011 consists of subject files concerning to Dr. Moloney's professional life as a performer, promoter, producer, and fieldworker. Materials include newsletters produced by various Irish-American "Celtic" Societies; scholarly journals on music and ethnicity; photocopies of early 20th century Irish-American newspapers; business and personal correspondence; an extensive collection (referred to as "Bookings") of contracts and correspondence detailing Dr. Moloney's performance engagements; files documenting behind-the-scenes studio work ("Recording Projects"); financial records and ephemera pertaining to major and independent labels, such as Green Linnet, Shanachie, Topic, and Transatlantic, with emphasis on marketing and the business models applied to Irish music starting in the 1970s. Of particular note is a complete run of the Shanachie label's newsletter and a collection of record catalogs dating back to the 1920s.
  The series also contains materials concerning Dr. Moloney's involvement in numerous federally funded projects, including the Smithsonian Institution Festival of American Folklife (1976), the Chicago Ethnic Arts Project (1977), the Green Fields of America ensemble, the 1982 Knoxville's World's Fair, the International Village Fair in Philadelphia (1987), the Philadelphia Ceili Group Festival, and the Irish Week at the Augusta Heritage Center in Elkins, West Virginia. Other projects are also documented, such as the development for the proposed multi-part series for Radio Telefis Eireann called The Green Fields of America and Emigrants and Exiles.
  - 1798 Rebellion, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A & E Television Networks, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Across the Western Ocean, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Folklife Center: Chicago Community Documentation Project, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Folklife Center: Knoxville Documentation Project, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Folklife Center: General, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Folklore Society: Newsletters, 1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Folklore Society: Annual Meeting, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Folklore Society: Panel Abstracts, 1990, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Folklore Society: Paper Draft, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Voices: Interviews with Jack and Fr. Charlie Coen, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Appalachia, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Appalachia, 1981-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Appalseed Productions, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Archives of Irish America, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Articles: Irish-American History, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Articles: Irish History, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Articles: Northern Ireland, 1978-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Arts Council of Northern Ireland, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Association of Performing Arts Presenters, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: 20th Anniversary Poster One, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: 20th Anniversary Poster Two (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: 20th Anniversary Poster Three (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: 20th Anniversary Poster Four, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: 20th Anniversary Poster Five, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Catalogs (folder one), 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Catalogs (folder two), 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Catalogs (folder three), 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Catalogs (folder four), 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Elderhostel Course Materials, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Elderhostel Evaluations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Evaluations (folder one), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Evaluations (folder two), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Evaluations (folder three), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: General (folder one), 1982-1989 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: General (folder two), 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: General (folder three), 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Augusta Heritage Center: Mailing Lists (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Autobiography: Notes and Drafts, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Balch Institute for Ethnic Studies (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Balkan Arts Center, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Banjo Meltdown, 1990, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Blarney Star, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Booking Agencies, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Booking Agencies: Ed MacIntosh Productions, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Clannad, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Flying Cloud, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Dolores Keane and John Faulkner, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Joe and Antoinette McKenna, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Various Artists (folder one), 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Various Artists (folder two), 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Booking Agency: Moloney: Various Artists (folder three), 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder three) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder three), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder three), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder three), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder three), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder three), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder one), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence (folder two), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bookings: Contracts, Correspondence, 1998-2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bookings: Potential, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Boston College: Gaelic Roots, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Britton Management, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cape Breton, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Catalogs: Books, 1988-1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Catalogs: Crafts, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Catalogs: Instruments, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Catalogs: Recordings, 1923-1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Catalogs: Recordings, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Catalogs: Recordings, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Catalogs: Recordings, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Catalogs: Recordings, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Catskills, 1978, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ceili Bands and Clubs, 1991-1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Celtic Appalachian Festival, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Celtic Mysteries by John Sharkey, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Final Report (folder one), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Final Report (folder two) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Final Report (folder three), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: General, 1977, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Photo Logs, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Ethnic Arts Project: Tape Logs, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Civil War (folder one), 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Civil War (folder two), 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Willie Clancy Week, 1977-2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Collecting, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder data_value_missing_1ed24b5f055d6046cb4788f66b944a79)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1980-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1997-2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Commodore Barry Club, PA., 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Concert Ideas, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Consulting Work, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Contacts and Directories, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Business, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Business, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1998-2002 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Personal, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cultural Centers (folder one), 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cultural Centers (folder two), 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Dance, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dance, 1976-1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dance, 1990-1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Dance, 1998-2005 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dance (folder one), undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dance (folder two), undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dance: American, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Delaware Folklife Program (folder one), 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Delaware Folklife Program (folder two), 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Delaware Folklife Program (folder three), 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Did Your Mother Come From Ireland?, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Directory of Traditional, Ethnic, and Traditionally-Inspired Music and Dance Presenters in Pennsylvania, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Discography of Irish Traditional Music - 78RPMs by Phillippe Varlet (folder one), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Discography of Irish Traditional Music - 78RPMs by Phillippe Varlet (folder two), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Discographies (folder one), circa 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Discographies (folder two), 1986-1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Discographies: Protest Songs, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Documentary Proposals, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dublin Folk Festival Programme, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Eagle Tavern, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Emigrants and Exiles: Documentary Film: Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Emigrants and Exiles: Documentary Film: Grant Applications (folder one), circa 1989 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Emigrants and Exiles: Documentary Film: Grant Applications (folder two), circa 1989 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Ethnic Folk Arts Center: Center for Traditional Music and Dance (folder one), 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ethnic Folk Arts Center: Center for Traditional Music and Dance (folder two), 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Exhibits, 1985-1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Famine: General (folder one), 1990-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Famine: General (folder two), undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Famine: Sesquicentennial, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Far From the Shamrock Shore: Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Far From the Shamrock Shore: Drafts, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Far From the Shamrock Shore: Revisions, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Far From the Shamrock Shore: General, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Festival of Mountains Music and Dance (folder one), 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Festival of Mountains Music and Dance (folder two), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Festival of Mountains Music and Dance (folder three), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Field Recordings: Interview Questions, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Field Recordings: Logs, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Florida Folklife Council (folder one), 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Florida Folklife Council (folder two), 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Folk Clubs: US and Canada, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Folk Festivals (folder one), 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Folk Festivals (folder two), 1985-1998 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Folklife Program for New Jersey, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Folklore Contacts, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Fresh Paint, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Gaelic Athletic Association, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Gaelic Gotham, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Gaelic League (folder one), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Gaelic League (folder two), 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Gaelic Roots: Boston College, 1998, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Glen Echo Television, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Glucksman Ireland House, 1995, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Grantwriting, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 31)